Finding Aid for the Edwin Wendell Pauley Papers, 1907-2001
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
- Photographs
  - Coconut Island
    - Party with Bobbe, F. Wellborn, Meredith Wilson, Julia Ing, Betty Williams, Mary Mako, Spengler, Norfleet, Nancy Lee Wilke, Glass (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Same party as box 13, f. 8 and f. 9
    - EWP, Bobbe, Mr. and Mrs. Bob Arthur, and friends (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Moku O Loe Island (Coconut Island) taken by Bill Pagen (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Various aerial photographs of Coconut Island (Box 82, Folder 4)
      f. 1 of 9
    - Various aerial photographs of Coconut Island (Box 82, Folder 5)
      f. 2 of 9
    - Various aerial photographs of Coconut Island (Box 82, Folder 6)
      f. 3 of 9
    - Various aerial photographs of Coconut Island (Box 82, Folder 7)
      f. 4 of 9
    - Various aerial photographs of Coconut Island (Box 82, Folder 8)
      f. 5 of 9
    - Various aerial photographs of Coconut Island (Box 82, Folder 9)
      f. 6 of 9
    - Various aerial photographs of Coconut Island (Box 82, Folder 10)
      f. 7 of 9
    - Various aerial photographs of Coconut Island (Box 82, Folder 11)
      f. 8 of 9
    - Various aerial photographs of Coconut Island (Box 82, Folder 12)
      f. 9 of 9
    - Various aerial photographs of Coconut Island (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - Black and white aerial photograph of Kaneohe Bay and surrounding areas (Box 82, Folder 14)
- Political files
  - Jordan - Correspondence (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Jordan - Photographs (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Jordan - Maps (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Jordan - News Clippings (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Iran - Overseas Economic Surveys (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Trip to the Middle East (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Palestine Problem - B'nai B'rith Messenger (The) (Box 121, Folder 2)
    Oversized; Newspaper; More in b67_f4
  - Concession Map of Cuba (Box 121, Folder 11)
  - County of Los Angeles Board of Supervisors - Resolution (Box 121, Folder 13)
  - Reparations
    - Allied Commission for Austria - Subject: Organization, Function and Operation of the Allied Secretariat (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - National Geographic Map - Germany and Its Approaches (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Some Aspects of the Austrian Economic Situation (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - An Economic and Industrial Program for Austria (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Occupation - United States Forces European Theater (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Allied Commission for Austria Allied Council (Unofficial US) Minutes of the 52nd Meeting (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Agreement Between United States Forces in Austria and the Federal Government of Austria (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - Outgoing Passengers List Staged at Camp Kilmer NJ - Shipment OM-E 055 AA (a) Company A1 (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - Tentative Train Schedule and Itinerary (Box 96, Folder 9)
    - Reparations Committee (Box 96, Folder 10)
    - Vienna Area Command Special Services Present Christmas Program (Box 96, Folder 23)
    - Army Press Release and Statement by EWP (Box 96, Folder 24)
  - Sessions and Caminita
    - Pauley Clippings General - Book 1 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Pauley Clippings - Japanese Report (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Pauley Clippings - A.P., U. P., I.N.S., and General News Stories - Book 2 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - Pauley Clippings - Manchurian Report - Book 5 (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - Pauley Clippings - EWP's experiences in Korea as revealed in The Diary - Book 6 (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - Pauley Clippings - Additional clippings of the Japanese Report - Book 7 (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - Pauley Clippings - Additional clippings of the Manchurian Report - Book 9 (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - Pauley Clippings - Additional clippings of the Japanese Report - Book 10 (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - Pauley Clippings - Miscellaneous Clippings - Book 12 (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - Pauley Clippings - Additional clippings on stories based on Korean Diary - Book 13 (Box 104, Folder 10)
    - Clippings on E. W. Pauley - Book 14 (Box 104, Folder 11)
    - Clippings on E. W. Pauley - Book 15 (Box 105, Folder 1)
      Oversized; copy 1
    - Clippings on E. W. Pauley - Book 15 (Box 105, Folder 2)
      Oversized; copy 2
    - Pauley Clippings - Japanese Reparations Report (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - Pauley Clippings - Soviet Reparations Plan (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - Pauley Clippings - Editorials (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - Clippings on E. W. Pauley (Box 105, Folder 6)
    - Clippings on E. W. Pauley (Box 105, Folder 7)
- Postcards
  - Moku O Loe Island (Coconut Island) (Box 16, Folder 8)
    Black and white, 3.25 in. (h) x 5.5 in. (w)
  - Coconut Island (Moku O Loe) in Kaneohe Bay, Oahu, Hawaii (Box 16, Folder 9)
    Color, 4 in. (h) x 5.5 in. (w)
  - Coconut Island (Box 16, Folder 10)
    Black and white, 3.5 in. (h) x 5.5 in. (w)
  - Miscellaneous Coconut Island postcards (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Royal Hawaiian Hotel (Box 16, Folder 12)
    Color, 3.5 in. (h) x 5.5 in. (w)
  - Moku O Loe Island (Coconut Island) (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Color, 5.5 in. (h) x 8 in. (w)
  - From Doris and Wendell to Bobbe (Box 59, Folder 8)
    Correspondence; Postcard of Hotel Des Bains, Italy
  - Brussels (Box 60, Folder 25)
- Scrapbooks
  - Misc. - Ram buy out, Shaw, HHH, Marcos (Box 147)
    Box 147 is an oversize flat box, 21" x 25-1/2".
  - UC Charter Day, Kennedy (Box 148)
    Box 148 is an oversize flat box, 21" x 25-1/2".
  - Edwin Pauley's death, including articles, telegrams, letters, etc. (Box 149)
    Box 149 is an oversize flat box, 21" x 25-1/2".
  - Truman Administration - selected newspaper issues (Box 150)
    Box 150 is an oversize flat box, 21" x 25-1/2".
- U.S. Politics
  - Inauguration - President Richard Nixon (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Richard Nixon (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Richard Nixon - White House notes (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Richard Nixon (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Presidential Ball - Washington D.C. (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Presidential Ball - Washington D.C. - List (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - December 12 Dinner (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Political Lists (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Political (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Senatorial Luncheon and Cocktail Party (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - John F. Kennedy (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - John F. Kennedy (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - John F. Kennedy (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Democratic National Committee (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - White House (Box 47, Folder 2)
    Correspondence, Booklets, News Clippings
  - Appreciation Letters to EWP (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Gerald R. Ford (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Letters of Recommendation (Political) (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - EWP and University Regents (Political) (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Democratic Convention - August 1968 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Political Appointment Requests (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Political Financial Requests (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Information and Assistance Re: Dinners, Luncheons, Speakers, and Political (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Membership on Political Campaigns (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Recommendations to Mayor Yorty (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - Democratic National Committee (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Democratic State Central Committee (Box 77, Folder 12)
    Correspondence, Pamphlets, Newsletters, and News Clippings
  - Democratic Convention Party at Residence (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Democratic Convention Party at Residence (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Kennedy Dinner (Box 78, Folder 3)
    Correspondence, Postcards, and News Clippings; f. 1 of 2
  - Kennedy Dinner (Box 78, Folder 4)
    Correspondence, Postcards, and News Clippings; f. 2 of 2
  - Letters of Recommendation (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Letters of Recommendation (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - 1947-1948 General Correspondence - A (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - 1947-1948 General Correspondence - B (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - 1947-1948 General Correspondence - C (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - 1947-1948 General Correspondence - D (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - 1947-1948 General Correspondence - E (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - 1947-1948 General Correspondence - F (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - 1947-1948 General Correspondence - G (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - 1947-1948 General Correspondence - H (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - 1947-1948 General Correspondence - I (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - 1947-1948 General Correspondence - J (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - 1947-1948 General Correspondence - K (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - 1947-1948 General Correspondence - L (Box 79, Folder 12)
  - Fertilizer Program (Box 79, Folder 13)
  - Magnesium Material (Box 79, Folder 14)
  - Sponsoring - Membership, etc. (Box 79, Folder 15)
  - Reparations (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Reparations (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Speeches - Correspondence regarding other than EWP (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Speeches - For official file and binding (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Speeches - Organized Reserves, Sixth Army and Veterans Foreign Wars - Los Angeles (Box 80, Folder 5)
    Photographs, Correspondence, Programs, and News Clippings
  - EWP - Final report to the Secretary of the Army (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Publicity - Press releases, magazines, art's, etc. (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Russia - Trends in Russian Foreign Policy Since World War I (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Prices (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Secretary Royall's trip to West Coast - Speeches before Los Angeles Town Hall and San Francisco Commonwealth Club (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Statement issued to the Press on "holdings", reference hearing before Senate Appropriation Committee (Box 81, Folder 2)
    Statement for December 12, 1947
  - Munitions Board Meetings (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Trip to Fort Monmouth, New Jersey - Signal Corps Laboratory (Box 81, Folder 4)
    Photographs and Correspondence; Trip on 1947 Nov 18
  - Congressional Dinner Honoring Robert E. Hannegan & Edwin W. Pauley (Box 96, Folder 25)
    Program
  - Jefferson Day Dinner (Box 96, Folder 26)
  - Press Releases (Box 96, Folder 27)
  - Invitations from FDR and Eleanor Roosevelt (Box 96, Folder 28)
  - Telegram from Katherine H. Darragh to EWP (Box 96, Folder 29)
  - List of persons traveling from Washington to Hyde Park (Box 96, Folder 30)
  - Inauguration Ceremonies - Platform A (Box 96, Folder 31)
    Tickets number 208 and 209
  - Telegram from Loretta Larkin to Robert E. Hannegan, c/o EWP (Box 96, Folder 32)
  - Address of Senator Claude Pepper of Florida at Dinner of Russian War Relief, Inc. (Box 96, Folder 33)
  - Admittance card to President Truman's first speech at the House of Representatives (Box 96, Folder 34)
  - 1944 Democratic National Convention - Ticket book and Medallion (Box 96, Folder 35)
    Memorabilia, 2 Ticket books and 4 Medallions
  - Address of EWP at the Banquet of the Boston Conference on "Women and the War" (Box 96, Folder 36)
  - General D. Macarthur, EWP, and General's Aide leaving the Dia Ichi building in Tokyo - Reparations Mission to Manchuria after WWII (Box 96, Folder 37)
  - Invitation from the Ambassador of the Netherlands to EWP and Bobbe (Box 96, Folder 38)
  - News Agency Reports on Roosevelt reelection (Box 96, Folder 39)
  - EWP Speech at the Democratic National Convention? (Box 96, Folder 40)
  - Cosmopolitan - The Five Men Who Kept Henry Wallace From Becoming President (Box 97, Folder 1)
    Magazine; Vol. 129, No. 1; 2 copies
  - Jonathan, The - Pauley Assumes Japanese Post (Box 97, Folder 2)
    Magazine; Vol. 15, No. 12
  - United States News - People of the Week (Box 97, Folder 3)
    Magazine; Vol. 19, No. 19
  - Democratic Digest, The (Box 97, Folder 4)
    Newsletter; Vol. 19, No. 2
  - Statement of EWP on Death of FDR (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Invitations to Presidential Dinners and Events (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Harry S. Truman Library and Museum - Schematic Design for the Presidential Galleries (Box 122, Folder 7)
  - Sam Rayburn - The House will be in order (Box 139, Folder 4)
  - Sam Rayburn Statue Dedication (Box 139, Folder 5)
  - Mr. Speaker by David L. Cohn (Box 140, Folder 1)
    on Sam Rayburn
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 144, Folder 3)
  - 1960 Democratic National Convention
    - Documentation (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Documentation (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Documentation (Box 50, Folder 2)
      Correspondence; f. 3 of 3
    - Contract Negotiations with National Committee (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Financing and Contributions (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Hotel and Office Accommodations (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Publicity (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Press Releases (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Program Printing (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Ticket Requests (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Transportation Arrangements (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Ticket Printing (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Democrats for Symington - California (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Joint County-City Citizen's Committee on Conventions (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Democratic National Convention 1960 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      Correspondence; f. 1 of 5
    - Democratic National Convention 1960 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      Correspondence; f. 2 of 5
    - Democratic National Convention 1960 (Box 51, Folder 9)
      Correspondence, News Clippings; f. 3 of 5
    - Democratic National Convention 1960 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      News Clippings; f. 4 of 5
    - Democratic National Convention 1960 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      News Clippings; f. 5 of 5
    - Democratic Digest (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Presidents Manual for Democratic Clubs (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Your Convention in Los Angeles (Box 52, Folder 5)
      Memorabilia, News Clippings; 2 copies
    - Poulson letter and attachments (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Hotel Requests (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Job Requests (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Ticket Requests (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Democratic Convention 1960 (Box 77, Folder 4)
      Correspondence, Pamphlets, and News Clippings
  - Presidential Candidates 1960
    - Democratic Convention 1960 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Rosa Crole (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Edmund G. Brown, Governor of California (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Honorable - John F. Kennedy (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Honorable - Stuart Symington (Box 77, Folder 9)
      Correspondence, Newsletters, and News Clippings
    - Honorable - John F. Kennedy (Box 121, Folder 8)
- University of California and U.S. Politics
  - Sam Yorty (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Political Letters of Recommendation (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Governorship - 1950 (Confidential) (Box 57, Folder 10)
    Correspondence, Report, News Clippings
  - Appointments - Hawaii Governorship (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Fortnight - California's own magazine (Box 57, Folder 12)
    Magazine; Vol. 14, No. 2
  - Citizens for Kennedy and Johnson - campaign manual (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - UCLA Alumni Magazine (Box 58, Folder 2)
    Magazine; Vol. 40, No. 1 - pages 26-27
  - Former Democratic Congressman, tells why, "I Cannot Take Kennedy" by Samuel W. Yorty (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Mexico trip with Edmund G. Brown (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Political Dinners (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Appointments with EWP (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Political Financial Requests (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Letters of Recommendation to Edmund G. Brown (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - 1966 Election Material (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Political (Box 58, Folder 10)
    Correspondence, Pamphlet, News Clippings
  - General Correspondence - 1960-1961 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence - 1970-1974 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence - 1975-1979 (Box 58, Folder 13)
    Correspondence, Folder; Includes 1977 Inaugural Guide to Washington; 2 copies
  - General Correspondence - 1980 (Box 58, Folder 14)
  - Governorship Race (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Democratic State Central Committee (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - California Politics (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - R - General (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Political Lists (Box 59, Folder 5)